A Guide to the Papers of Hugh Scott, 1941-1985
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Hugh Scott, 1941-1985
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10200-z
This collection consists of (ca.) 260 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was a gift of Mr. Scott, Scott, Harrison & McLeod, Washington, D.C. on 1985 December 30.
Biographical/Historical Information
Hugh Scott was a United States Senator from Pennsylvania.
Scope and Content Information
The collection contains Hugh Scott's appointment books, 1975-1979; articles and a book review by Scott; and topical files on the United States bicentennial, Chinese art and archaelogy; normalization of United States-China relations; foreign affairs; George Bush's 1980 presidential campaign, proposed legislation; naval service; and the Williamsburg VIII conference, Thailand.
A V.I.P. correspondence file consists chiefly of social notes and routine letters, 1963-1985.
Correspondents include James Lane Buckley, Mamie Eisenhower, Eugene V. Rostow and William W. Scranton.
Contents List
- Articles by Hugh Scott 1953, 1985 (Box 1)
- Bicentennial Celebration 1976 (Box 1)
- Celebrations and Invitations 1947, 1968-1985 (Box 1)
- Certificates and Honors 1982-1985 (Box 1)
- Chinese Archaeological Exhibition 1974-1975 (Box 1)
- Chinese Art Collections 1968-1976 (Box 1)
- Chinese Normalization 1978 (Box 1)
- Chinese Normalization: Schedule and Materials for Good Morning America Show, August 22, 1977 1975-1977 (Box 1)
- Correspondence: V.I.P., and other Political Figures 1963-1985 (Box 1)
- Foreign Affairs 1974-1983 (Box 1)
- George Bush for President 1974-1980, n.d., 2 folders (Box 1)
- Georgetown 1965-1967 (Box 2)
- The Last Two Million Years Published by Reader's Digest: Advance Review by Hugh Scott 1974 (Box 2)
- Legislation Proposed by Hugh Scott and ranks of members of Congress 1976 (Box 2)
- Naval Service 1941-1945 (Box 2)
- Political Miscellaneous 1953-1985 (Box 2)
- Securities and Real Estate Reports to Francis R. Valeo, Secretary of the Senate 1969-1975 (Box 2)
- Ships named Pennsylvania or Philadelphia for use in the Senate Office Building's Hugh Scott Room 1981 (Box 2)
- Williamsburg VIII Conference in Thailand on the Pacific Region 1978 (Box 2)
- Appointment Books for Hugh Scott 1975-1979, 7 bound volumes (Box 3)